

# MARK RAPHAEL D. NUGUID

Web Developer

+63-945 758 4087

marked-portfolio.vercel.app

□ nmark.raphael07@gmail.com

♀ 357 San Simon St, Sta. Cruz, Porac, Pampanga

#### **SUMMARY**

I am Mark Raphael D. Nuguid, an adaptable and efficient Web Developer specializing in React and Next.js. With extensive experience in creating bespoke web applications and websites for marketing and other purposes, I leverage a wide range of technologies, including various backend stacks, to deliver optimal solutions.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Web Developer Intern, Center for Kapampangan Studies

Sept 2022 - Feb 2023

- Developed the web app Kapampangan translator
- Created CMS to manage the Kapampangan translator contents
- Managed the applications content

## Freelance Web Developer

Jan 2021 - Dec 2023

- · Developed and maintained responsive front-end applications using React.js
- Created responsive web applications and management systems using PHP, Laravel, and React.js, enhancing functionality and user experience across various projects.

## Web Developer Volunteer, Center for Kapampangan Studies

Sept 2022 - Present

- Developed Minindal, a web application that aims to streamline search for authentic Kapampangan cuisine built with React JS and Laravel.
- Created a CMS for the web application and managed contents

#### Web Developer, Fullstack HQ

Aug 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop and maintain a diverse range of projects, including marketing sites, mobile applications, Shopify projects, and custom web applications.
- Implemented responsive, SEO-friendly interfaces for marketing websites, creating reusable components and adhering to best practices for accessibility and development.
- Integrated third-party APIs and platforms such as HubSpot, Google APIs, CMS, and Xano into custom web applications to enhance functionality and meet specific client requirements.

## **EDUCATION**

TERTIARY 2019 - 2023

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Holy Angel University

With are of specialization in Web Development

SECONDARY 2013 - 2019

## **Angeles City National Trade School**

Holy Angel University

· With are of specialization in Web Development

PRIMARY 2007 - 2013

#### **Sto. Rosario Elementary School**

Holy Angel University

With are of specialization in Web Development

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- PHP
- HTML
- CSS
- JS, JQUERY, AJAX
- GIT

- React JS
- NextJS
- React Native
- Tailwind CSS
- Laravel

- API Integration
- CMS (Wordpress, Builder, & StoryBlok)
- Xano (No-code Backend)
- Vercel

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: English and Filipino

Soft Skills: Effective Communication, Problem-Solving, Attention to Detail, Adaptability, Critical

Thinking, Team Collaboration

#### Awards/Activities:

- Presented Kapampangan translator to Holy Angel University's foundation day
- Presented Minindal web application to the First International Conference on Kapampangan Cuisine and Food Tourism at Holy Angel University

#### REFERENCE

#### Dr. Joseph A. Esquivel

Holy Angel University

Phone: +63-917 621 6023

Email: jesquivel@hau.edu.ph

## Leonardo R Calma Jr

Center for Kapampangan Studies

Phone: +63-916 301 4274

Email: kapampangancenter@gmail.com

The information above are true and correct

Mark Raphael D. Nuguid

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/mark-raphael-nuguid/